<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Society | Ryan Bailey</title>
    <link>/tag/society/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/society/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Society</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Society</title>
      <link>/tag/society/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guns, Germs, and Steel</title>
      <link>/books/gunsgermssteel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/books/gunsgermssteel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having done field work in New Guinea for more than 30 years, Jared Diamond presents the geographical and ecological factors that have shaped the modern world. From the viewpoint of an evolutionary biologist, he highlights the broadest movements both literal and conceptual on every continent since the Ice Age, and examines societal advances such as writing, religion, government, and technology. Diamond also dissects racial theories of global history, and the resulting work—Guns, Germs and Steel—is a major contribution to our understanding the evolution of human societies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Death of Expertise</title>
      <link>/books/deathofexpertise/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/books/deathofexpertise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People are now exposed to more information than ever before, provided both by technology and by increasing access to every level of education. These societal gains, however, have also helped fuel a surge in narcissistic and misguided intellectual egalitarianism that has crippled informed debates on any number of issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, everyone knows everything and all voices demand to be taken with equal seriousness, and any claim to the contrary is dismissed as undemocratic elitism. Tom Nichols shows this rejection of experts has occurred for many reasons, including the openness of the Internet, the emergence of a customer satisfaction model in higher education, and the transformation of the news industry into a 24-hour entertainment machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paradoxically, the increasingly democratic dissemination of information, rather than producing an educated public, has instead created an army of ill-informed and angry citizens who denounce intellectual achievement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nichols notes that when ordinary citizens believe that no one knows more than anyone else, democratic institutions themselves are in danger of falling either to populism or to technocracy - or in the worst case, a combination of both.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Doomsday Machine</title>
      <link>/books/doomsdaymachine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/books/doomsdaymachine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the same time former presidential advisor Daniel Ellsberg famously took the top-secret Pentagon Papers, he also took with him a chilling cache of top secret documents related to America&amp;rsquo;s nuclear program in the 1960s. Here for the first time he reveals the contents of those documents and makes clear their shocking relevance for today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Doomsday Machine is Ellsberg&amp;rsquo;s hair-raising insider&amp;rsquo;s account of the most dangerous arms buildup in the history of civilization, whose legacy - and renewal under the Obama administration - threatens the very survival of humanity. It is scarcely possible to estimate the true dangers of our present nuclear policies without penetrating the secret realities of the nuclear strategy of the late Eisenhower and early Kennedy years, when Ellsberg had high-level access to them. No other insider has written so candidly of that long-classified history, and nothing has fundamentally changed since that era. Ellsberg&amp;rsquo;s analysis of recent research on nuclear winter shows that even a &amp;lsquo;small&amp;rsquo; nuclear exchange would cause billions of deaths by global nuclear famine. Ellsberg, in the end, offers steps we can take under a new administration to avoid nuclear catastrophe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
